Source: https://www.YouTube.com/watch?v=feeLrcJpc1Y
OG Creator: 1C2
Contact me to delete the video: wangpy01@outlook.com
Sorry for any inconvience.
从未见过哪一幅旧画不是代表艺术家被扭曲的梦想？
艺术家偿费尽心机也无法逾越重重障碍，安全表达出自己的意图。
欣赏一幅古典绘画，无疑所我们的情感灌注进一具棺材里，
不如勇敢地投身于创作，在实践中发挥灵感。
这样漫无边际地欣赏过去的东西毫无益处，而且使人感到疲劳、沮丧和消沉，
难道你们愿意这样浪费自己宝贵的精力吗？
This is a quote from the Futurist Manifesto written by Italian poet, Filippo Tommaso Marinetti,
这些文字引自意大利诗人菲利波·托马索·马里内蒂的 《未来主义宣言》
and published in 1909.
发表于 1909 年
With his work, he and his cohort announced to the world a new movement...
通过他的作品   他和他的同伙向世界宣布了一个新的运动
that fetishized industrial progress and man's triumph over nature.
崇拜工业进步和人类对自然的胜利
Recognizing that the world had entered into a new age of unprecedented technological innovation.
他们认识到世界已经进入了一个前所未有的技术革新的新时代
they unabashedly declared that Humanity should free itself...
因此毫不掩饰地宣称
from the shackles of the traditions, tastes and morals of the past...
人类应该摆脱过去的传统、品味和道德的束缚
in pursuit of, well, the future.
追求未来
未    来
Progress to them should come at any expense,
对他们来说   进步应该不惜一切代价
even that of human life.
哪怕是牺牲人的生命
8、 我们穿过无数世纪走到了尽头！……
9、 我们要歌颂战争——清洁世界的唯一手段，……
10、 我们要摧毁一切博物馆、图书馆和科学院，……
In addition to valorizing war and violence,
除了高度评价战争和暴力
the core Italian futurists were also ardent nationalists,
意大利的核心未来主义者也是热心的民族主义者
11、我们歌颂声势浩大的劳动人群、娱乐的人群或造反的人群；
歌颂夜晚灯火辉煌的船坞和热气腾腾的建筑工地；
歌颂贪婪在吞进冒烟的长蛇的火车站；歌颂用缕缕青烟作绳索攀上白云的工厂；
歌颂像身躯巨大的健将一般横跨于阳光下如钢刀发亮的河流上的桥梁；……
我们从意大利向全世界发出这份具有冲击力和煽动性的宣言书，
宣告我们于今天创立未来主义。
我们的目的是要切除这个国家肌体上生长着的由教授、
考古学家、导游者和古董商们组成的臭气熏天的痈疽。
意大利充当一个旧货市场的时期已经太长了。
我们要把这个国家从数不清的博物馆中拯救出来，
这些博物馆将无数的坟场墓地布满它的大地。
seeing this movement as Italy’s opportunity to reassert itself onto the world stage,
他们将这场运动视为意大利在世界舞台上重新证明自己的机会
instead of acting as a sort of nursing home for antiquity.
而不是充当某种古代的养老院
Oh and they also hated feminism and women broadly.
他们还讨厌女性   憎恶女权
……我们歌颂为之献身的美丽理想，我们称赞一切蔑视妇女的言行。
……向道德主义、女权主义以及一切卑鄙的机会主义的思想开战。
Uh, so it should come to no surprise then that...
所以说   许多意大利未来主义者在未来几十年里
many of these Italian futurists became Fascists in the coming decades.
变成法西斯主义者   就不足为奇了
But back to the quote,
回到引文
the futurists weren't just to let the past die sort of group,
未来主义者不仅仅想让过去像人类一样自然消亡
博物馆就是坟墓！……它从头何其相似，
都是素昧生平的躯体的可悲的聚会场所。
博物馆是让冤家仇人或者陌生的人们互相紧挨着长眠的公共寝室！
博物馆是屠杀画家和雕刻家荒廖绝伦的屠宰场，
让他们沿着竞争的墙壁，
用色彩和线条互相残杀！
假如一年去朝拜一次，就像在亡灵节去扫墓那样，我同意去。
假如每年供献一次鲜花于《蒙娜丽莎》之前，我同意你们做。
……但是，我不允许人们终日徘徊在博物馆里，
表现出诚惶诚恐、惆怅不已的病态激动。
为什么要自寻烦恼？为什么要受腐蚀呢？
they wanted to kill the past,
他们想要扼杀过去
literally demolishing museums and libraries was a core tenet of their manifesto.
摧毁博物馆和图书馆是他们宣言的核心原则
And while the proper futurist movement peaked back in the 20s and 30s,
虽然正派的未来主义者运动在二三十年代达到了顶峰
you can still find elements of their philosophy permitting throughout our culture today.
但你仍然可以发现他们的哲学元素渗透到我们今天的文化中
Specifically, this one core theme, this reckless contempt for what came before.
特别是这个核心主题   这种对前人的不顾一切的蔑视
蔑 视 过 去
It's something that hasn't completely gone away.
它还没有完全消失
And I see that theme popping up time and time again, and, to be frank, it troubles me.
我看到这个主题一次又一次地出现   坦率地说   这让我很烦恼
I don't know if it's just me, but the last few years of the internet have felt pretty stagnant.
不知道是否只有我在这么想   但互联网的最后几年感觉停滞不前
停  滞  不  前
Maybe it's nostalgia goggles kicking in,
也许是怀旧滤镜加成
but I feel like the current internet climate feels much less optimistic and exciting...
但我觉得与 2000 年代和 2010 年代相比
compared to the 2000s and the 2010s.
当前的互联网环境感觉不那么乐观和令人兴奋
Back then, we saw an explosion of new web-based services and products...
那时   我们看到基于网络的新服务和产品的爆炸性增长
that were redefining entire industries.
重新定义了整个行业
Everything from managing sales funnels to doing taxes to watching movies.
从管理销售渠道到纳税   再到看电影   无所不包
The sky was the limit.
简直没有天花板
But now, markets have become saturated.
但现在市场已经饱和了
The competitive fronts between different companies have become increasingly entrenched.
不同公司之间的竞争战线已经变得越来越稳固
And so in pursuit of continuously increasing profits,
因此   为了追求不断增加的利润
companies have turned to squeezing more money from the end user.
公司转向从终端用户那里榨取更多的钱
While the industry as a whole desperately searches for its next iPhone moment,
当整个行业拼命寻找其下一个“重新定义”的时刻时
many companies and investors thought they were onto something with the metaverse or,
许多公司和投资者认为他们在滥用元宇宙
putting block chain technology into everything for absolutely no fucking reason,
或将区块链技术融入一切玩意   就那啥毫无理由
or whatever other buzzword was being thrown around.
反正用什么脏话来形容都一样
For a bit, it seemed like the emperor had no clothes,
有一段时间   科技公司还像没穿衣服的皇帝一样迷失于此
but it looks like the bubble has finally popped on that Silicon Valley dream.
但看起来   硅谷梦想的泡沫终于破灭了
加密货币公司筹集的风投资金
数据截至 2023 年 5 月 16 日 （单位：十亿美元）
And now the industry has looked to AI as the next major frontier for tech.
现在   互联网行业将人工智能视作下一个科技前沿
But as impressive as generative chat bots like ChatGPT can be,
但是   尽管像 ChatGPT 这样的生成式聊天机器人让人影响深刻
AI isn't the Saving Grace for the internet.
人工智能并不是因特网的救星
And in a lot of ways, its novelty is distracting us...
从很多方面讲   它的新奇反而在分散我们的注意力
from some really worrying trends that are making the Internet a far worse place to be.
让我们忽视一些真正令人担忧的   让互联网变得更糟糕的趋势
There isn't really an overarching thesis to this video.
本视频没有一个总体论点
This is mostly just a collection of stories that really bother me...
主要是一组困扰我的故事
and seem to suggest that the internet is headed for a far less interconnected future,
它们表明互联网正走向一个远非互联的未来
where all websites become walled gardens,
所有网站都变成有围墙的花园
where every last time is squeezed out of each individual user,
每个用户的每分每秒都被挤压出来
and where the internet as a whole,
互联网作为一个整体
it was less useful and less usable.
其作用和可用性都降低了
第      一      章
被  封  锁  的   A P I
Oh, Twitter.
噢   推特
Oooh boy Twitter.
来看看推特
What a ride has been ever since Elon Musk took the company's reigns back in October.
自从埃隆·马斯克在十月夺回公司控制权以来   这段旅程真是美妙呵
埃隆·马斯克完成了
440 亿美元的交易
正式收购推特
这位世界首富完成了
对社交媒体服务的巨额收购，
将推特推向了一个新时代。
It's been nothing but questionable decision after questionable decision.
全是一个接着一个的令人质疑的决定
马斯克收购推特后
在整个公司裁员
*这个给组织/公司用的金 V 一个月就是七千多人民币。
I cannot tell you how many times I've had rewrite this script,
我的稿子不知道改了多少回
马斯克威胁美国公共广播电台
要把他们的账号分给其他人
电台这样回应
because of some new batshit insane thing that Twitter decided to do.
都跟不上推特做的屑事情
Twitter’s advertising revenue in the US is down 59% compared to last year,
在广告商大量外流后
推特在美广告销额暴跌 59%
困境仍在继续
following a mass exodus of advertisers.
与去年相比   推特在美广告收入减少了 59%
数据显示 推特前一千名广告主中
一半以上都不再投放
And Twitter Blue has only been able to scrounge back $11,000,000...
而推特蓝标会员只能从该公司可能损失的数亿美元中
推特蓝标会员重启三个月
移动销售额仅 1100 万美元
of the hundreds of millions of dollars the company potentially lost in revenue.
捡回 1100 万美元
And that number is probably pretty outdated.
而且这个数据很可能过时了
A newer data has shown that more than half of Twitter Blue’s earliest subscribers...
一项较新的数据显示   最早开通蓝标会员的用户中
最早开通蓝标会员的用户中
一半以上已经不再续订
are no longer subscribed to the service.
一半以上都不再续订它了
Musk has made it clear that he wants to transform Twitter...
马斯克明确表示他想要把推特转型
into X, an omnipotent super app.
转成“X” 一个全能的超级应用
超     级     应     用
You're all in one place for communication, finances,
所有的沟通交流、财务
and media consumption that can dip to WeChat in China.
和媒体消费都在一个应用   如同中国的微信
And we've seen Twitter go full steam ahead into transforming itself.
我们已经看到推特全力推进自我转型
推特告诉其合作伙伴
其公司更名为 X
正在向万能应用转型
Twitter Inc. has been renamed X Corp.
推特公司已更名为 X 公司
Musk has announced that more robust DMs and video calls will be eventually coming.
马斯克宣布   推特会加入更强大的私信系统和视频通话
推特推出私信功能更新
并宣布支持语音与视频通话
另外 只有认证用户才能给非粉丝发私信了（哎）
And users can now trade stocks on Twitter in a partnership with Etoro.
推特还与 Etoro 合作   让用户能在推特上炒股
推特允许用户交易股票
向马斯克的超级应用推进
I think the most significant Italian change...
但我认为最专制的一项改变
that Twitter has implemented so far revolves around access to its API
是围绕着访问推特的 API 展开的
For those of you who don't know,
你可能不知道什么是 API
API stands for “application programming interface”,
它指的是“应用程序编程接口”
应    用    程    序    编    程    接    口
and it's the protocol that's used to communicate between different computer programs.
它是在不同程序之间交流的协议
So if you need to push data or send a command from one system to another,
如果你要把数据从一个系统推送到另一个系统
anything from Google Sheets, Salesforce to Stripe,
比如从谷歌表单或 Salesforce 到 Stripe
you would use an API for it.
你就要用到 API
API are pretty ubiquitous throughout the internet.
API 在互联网上无处不在
推特与红迪的高价 API
对互联网的未来是个坏消息
一个不那么有趣、实惠的网络
可能会等待着我们。
那么，你为什么要关心 API 现在发生了什么呢？
好吧，从社交媒体的早期开始，许多平台
就为开发人员免费提供了访问其 API 的权限。
只要社交媒体存在，某种形式的免费 API 访问
就已经存在了。Friendster 和 MySpace 都有。
长期以来一直存在这样一条不成文的规则，
即用户通过其内容和使用情况向这些社交
媒体平台提供数据，平台利用这些数据获利，
并表明该平台对此类用户数据没有所有权，
第三方独立开发人员和初创公司能够自由访问
这些数据，以创建酷炫有趣的应用程序，
使平台及其用户都受益。
For consumer grade online services,
对于消费者级在线服务
it's pretty rare that access to the API is put behind a paywall.
很少有人将 API 拿来收费   要交钱才能用
And this is especially the case for social media,
社交媒体尤其如此
but back in February of this year, Twitter did just that.
但今年二月   推特就这么做了
从 2 月 9 日起，我们不再提供对推特 API 的免费访问
你得买一个付费的基本计划
Developers and researchers were stunned to discover...
开发者和研究人员惊讶地发现
that they would have to start paying to access Twitter's API.
他们必须付费才能访问推特 API
Hundreds of accounts announced that they were shutting down all because of this change,
成千上万的账户宣布   因为这一变化它们不得不下线
from the national weather service, sending out weather updates,
从发送天气更新的国家气象局
to local transportation authorities, sending out transportation updates,
到发送交通更新的地方交通部门
and of course, fun gimmick accounts.
当然   还有摸鱼用的段子账户
Musk claim that the reason for this was to limit bot spam,
马斯克解释这是为了控制垃圾机器人
免费 API 已经被广告机器人和舆论操纵者
严重滥用了，以前没有任何验证或收费，
你很轻松就能注册十万个垃圾机器人
每个月只收 100 美元，事情就会好得多
but developers have claimed that...
但开发者辩称
这尽是为了干掉合法的工具
拜拜咯，一键删帖器
拜拜咯，词云生成器
拜拜咯，宠物机器人
广告机器人用的是注入推特网
页端的脚本，或者是窃取的官
方 API，对他们挡了个寂寞
the real spam comes from scripts injected into Twitter as web client,
真正的垃圾机器人来自注入推特   冒充其网页客户端的脚本
or from stolen API keys.
或来自被窃取的 API 秘钥
And while some of the original API plans have been walked back like...
推特有所让步   原来的一些 API 计划被收回了
through the reintroduction of a free tier albeit, an extremely limited one.
比如重新引入了一个免费额度   尽管是一个极其有限的额度
This is, in addition to removing API access to third party clients,
然而   他们取消了对第三方客户端的 API 访问
推特更新开发者条约
正式禁止第三方客户端
尚不清楚推特在执行
什么样的“长期 API 政策”
来把 TweetBot* 封了
*TweetBot 是一款饱受欢迎的第三方推特客户端，类似于 See 和 Share 之于微博。
2023 年 1 月 19 日被封杀后，开发公司宣布转攻 Mastodon 的客户端，Ivory。
a clear signal that the future of Twitter will be more and more hostile to its developer community...
这也是一个明确的信号   即推特的未来将对其开发者社区越来越不友好
and that it wants to become a walled garden for the internet.
它想成为互联网的围墙花园
Also, something really funny that I found is that...
另外   我发现一件极其可笑的事
in order to request access to Twitter enterprise API,
要请求访问企业级推特 API
you have to fill out a fucking Google form.
你得先填一个谷歌表单
It sends you to a Google form.
推特居然让你填谷歌的表单
People who are gonna be paying $42,000 a month are sent to a Google form!
它们就拿谷歌表单来招待一年要交四万二千刀的客户
It's so funny.
属实难蚌
In the wake of this change, we've seen Reddit, follow suit.
在这一变化之后   我们看到红迪也在跟进
API 之死：
红迪追随推特
用高额收费挤死
第三方客户端
Reddit will begin charging for access to its API,
红迪也将开始对其 API 访问收费
pricing out many developers who manage third party clients with the site,
让开发第三方红迪客户端的开发者望而却步
Apollo 客户端关闭
红迪第
三方客户端 Apollo 宣布将在
6 月 30 日关闭，因其无法支
付新 API 政策下每年产生的
两千万美元
even the ones that offer tools to help communities manage and moderate themselves...
甚至是那些提供工具帮助社区管理论坛、调节社区的开发者
that Reddit flatly does not offer out of the box.
而红迪完全没有提供这些工具
Reddit’s reasoning for this is twofold.
红迪给出了两方面解释
For one, it is rightly identified that there is a lot of useful,
首先   必须承认红迪上有很多有用的
easily accessible information on the platform.
且容易得到的信息
I mean how many times have you gone to search something on Google...
想想你有多少次在谷歌搜东西时
and appended Reddit to the end of your query?
在查询内容的末尾加上一个“reddit”
DuckDuckGo 甚至把一键加 reddit 作为宣传点
Which is something we're gonna discuss later, by the way, anyway.
关于这一点   我们稍后会详细讨论
Because of this, Reddit is hoping to protect itself from data scraping.
因此   红迪希望保护自己不受数据搜刮的影响
社交网络认为，人工智能公司已经得到了
他们数据的免费使用权，因此正在提高访
问其 API 的成本。但不是只针对人工智
能公司，而是全面提高了访问 API 的成
本，破坏了第三方应用开发者的商业模式，
他们中的许多人一开始就向社交网络发送
了大量有价值的流量。
OpenAI previously revealed that Reddit was indeed...
OpenAI 承认红迪确实是
one of the sources used to train its AI models.
用来训练其人工智能模型的数据来源之一
And Reddit doesn't want that to happen again without getting a cut.
红迪不希望这种事在它没得一点分成的情况下再次发生
Also, as Reddit continues to put around the idea of going public,
另外   随着红迪向上市努力
红迪计划在 2023 下半年首次公开募股
it wants to find new ways to monetize itself.
它想找到新的方法使自己盈利
In case, it's not obvious,
但如果不明显的话
all of this not only makes things worse for developers, but, also for users,
所有这些事不仅对开发者讲变得更糟   对用户也是如此
it limits what can be done on these sites...
它限制了在这些网站上可以做的事情
and advances the idea that there can and should only be one way,
并推进了这样一种想法   即可以而且应该只有一种方式
one set of approved channels for a user to interact with the site.
一套被批准的渠道让用户与网站互动
It makes these sites less useful by eliminating automated accounts that supply good information.
它消除了提供良好信息的自动账户   使这些网站变得不再有用
It limits the data that you can get about your own and other's Internet presence.
它限制了你能得到的关于你自己和其他人的互联网存在的数据
It limits the research that can be done on these sites and on their communities.
它限制了可以在这些网站和社区上进行的研究
And it flat out limits human creativity by restricting developers...
它还通过限制开发者创造不同的和独特的用户体验
from creating different and unique user experiences.
完全限制了人类的创造力
第      二      章
内  容  的  剔  除
Back in May of this year,
今年五月
不活跃账号政策更新
Google announced that it will be deleting inactive Google accounts on mass.
谷歌宣布它会大量删除不活跃的谷歌账户
Specifically, those that haven't seen any activity in 2 years.
具体的说   两年都没有任何活动的账户
Countless emails, attachments, Google drive files, photos, and more,
无数的邮件及其附件、谷歌云盘的文件、照片   还有其他的
will be deleted at the end of this year.
都将在今年年底被删除
And what struck me the most was just how poorly this change was announced.
最让我震惊的是   他们发布这一变化的方式相当糟糕
It was just casually dropped in a security blog post.
就随便放在了安全博客文章中
And the lack of detail had people speculating as to whether this would mean that...
细节的缺失也让人们怀疑
entire channels on YouTube would be removed if the associated Google account hadn't been active.
如果油管频道关联的谷歌账户不活跃了   整个频道是不是都要删掉
我们更新了这篇博文来阐明这个公告是如何影
响视频创作者账号和带有油管视频的账号的。
The fact that they only updated the blog post after this backlash just shows that...
他们在这一反响后才更新博文
they really didn't care enough to think about this the first go-round,
表明他们在第一轮时确实没有关心到这一点
or maybe that they were actually thinking about deleting YouTube videos at first.
或者说他们一开始确实打算删除油管视频
But God, even after they clarify these changes, things still look pretty bad.
但是   天啊   即使他们澄清了这些变化   事情仍然很糟糕
Imagine you have a dead family member...
想想你有一个去世的家庭成员
and you didn't know how to recover their account until it was too late,
在永久删除之前   你不知道如何恢复他们的账户
or I don't know you were in a coma, or God forbid, you were imprisoned for whatever reason.
亦或是你处于昏迷当中   又或许你进了监狱
Imagine your Google account, the crux of your online identity being erased in an instant.
想象你的谷歌账号   你在线身份的关键   在一瞬间被擦除了
Poof! Gone forever.
哦豁   永远没了
You have to start from scratch and also fight an uphill battle,
你得从头开始打一场硬仗
proving that you are who you say you are.
证明你是你所说的人
Twitter has also announced that they'll be doing the same thing.
推特也宣布他们要做同样的事情
推特将要移除并归档闲置账户
They would begin purging inactive accounts.
他们也要清除不活跃的账号
Whereas Google at least had the courtesy to say that it was for security reasons,
谷歌至少有点礼貌   说这是出于安全原因
it seems like Twitter is literally just trying to trim off as much fat as they can.
推特只是想尽可能的减少累赘
Their official policy states that an account risks deletion...
他们的官方政策规定   如果一个账户在一个月内没有活动
推特的不活跃账户政策是什么？
在大家注册账号时，我们鼓
励大家活跃地登录并使用推
特。为保持你的账号活跃，
请确保每 30 天至少登录一
次。长期不活跃的账户可能
会被永久删除。
if it's inactive for 30 days, a month.
就有被删除的风险
Imgur also decided recently that a bunch of old photos...
Imgur 最近也决定
互联网的更多内容将要消失
身堪重负的图床 Imgur 宣布将删除旧图与黄图
and forum content just wasn't worth keeping around anymore.
一堆旧照片和论坛内容不值得再保留了
Despite these forums being the original reason, Imgur got popular in the first place.
尽管始作俑者是那些论坛   Imgur 的举动首先让社区炸开了锅
All the while, streaming services like Disney+, HBO Max — now dubbed, just a Max,
流媒体服务   诸如 Disney+、HBO Max（现在称作 Max）
Hulu and Showtime, have removed access to dozens and dozens of movies and TV shows,
Hulu 和 Showtime 取消了对数十部电影和电视节目的访问权限有一段时日了
and it's not just content that they've licensed from other companies.
而且这不仅仅是他们从其他公司授权的内容
It also includes movies and shows produced in-house.
它还包括内部制作的电影和节目
流媒体服务正在移除大量电影与节目
绝非个人行为  而是一门生意
后面的新闻标题不译了，太累了，
油管原视频的视频简介都有链接，自己去看吧
By limiting their libraries to current or uber popular content,
通过将他们的影视库限制在时下流行或饱受欢迎的内容上
these companies can take advantage of certain tax breaks in some cases,
这些公司在某些情况下可以利用一些税收减免
or eliminate the costs of licensing fees or residuals that they pay out to the contents creators.
或者砍掉他们支付给内容创作者的许可费或剩余费用
Literally less than 6 months after wrapping up its first season,
在第一季结束后还不到半年
the Disney+ fantasy series Willow was pulled from streaming.
Disney+ 的幻想系列剧《风云际会》从流媒体下架了
That's just crazy.
太疯狂了
I mean, everyone complains about the content mill,
确实   人人都在骂剧本
but it's just so unbelievably cruel to see a piece of art...
但看到一件人们花了多年时间创作的艺术品
that people have spent years of their lives working on,
却被当作什么都没有一样扔掉
being tossed away like it's nothing.
真是令人难以置信的残忍
All this while there's a writer strike going on behind you to add insult to injury.
与此同时   作家罢工正在你看不到的地方进行   这是雪上加霜
This also means that in many cases,
这也意味着   许多情况下
there's no longer a legal means of watching this content.
不再有合法的手段来观看这些内容
While these sites are deleting content of their own volition,
这些网站是自愿删除内容
other organizations are being forced to remove content from the web.
其他一些组织就是被迫的了
Another pillar of the Internet, the Internet Archive,
互联网的另一个支柱   互联网档案馆
was dealt a major blow in the lawsuit back in March.
早在三月份的诉讼中受到了重大打击
Book publishers argued that there was no legal basis for the Internet Archive...
图书出版商认为   互联网档案馆借出数字图书没有法律依据
to lend out digital books, even through controlled digital lending.
即使是通过有控制的数字借阅也一样
And the courts agreed.
法院同意了
while the Internet Archive is appealing,
尽管互联网档案馆正在上诉
it's still so tragic to think that such a wealth of knowledge could be rendered, utterly useless.
但想到如此丰富的知识可能会变得完全无用   仍然是如此悲惨
Now, I'm not a lawyer,
我不是律师
so I can't speak to the particulars of the case with any authority,
所以我不能以任何权威的方式谈论案件的细节
but boy, does it feel like publishers would outlaw brick and mortar libraries if they could.
但你看   如果可能的话   出版商简直会把实体图书馆都取缔
Free and open access to information is at the core of the Internet ethos,
自由和开放地获取信息是互联网精神的核心
and well it's just so sad to see so much of that information going up in smoke.
看到如此多的信息付之一炬   我感到很悲伤
Companies only see value in data that makes the money,
公司们只看到那些能赚钱的数据的价值
and so these accounts and their associated data are designated as digital access.
所以这些账户及其相关数据才被他们指定为“数字访问”
If anything, these actions by major online platforms...
若要说点什么   主流网络平台的这些行动
highlight the fragility of our digital experiences,
凸显了我们数字体验的脆弱性
and serve as a reminder of the unfortunate impermanence
并提醒我们一个不幸的事实
of the information we create and consume daily.
我们每天创建和消费的信息如此无常
第      三      章
搜  索  之  死
The state of online search right now is pretty disgusting.
现在在线搜索的状态非常令人作呕
If you innocently type something into Google,
如果你天真地在谷歌中输入了一些东西
Google then blasts you with a deluge of ads,
谷歌就会用它认为你想要的大量推广
carousels, and widgets that it thinks you want.
轮播广告和小部件来轰炸你
And then once you get to the organic search results,
然后   一旦你进入正常的搜索结果
it's filled to the brim with generic solace,
它就会充斥着一般的聊以安慰的东西
keyword written listings that more often than not,
以及堆砌关键词的结果列表
frankly don't answer your question.
坦率地说   这些列表往往不会回答你的问题
It's quite the development that in the world of online search,
在在线搜索领域   管理的负担已经转移到用户身上
the burden of curation has shifted back to the user.
这是一个相当大的发展
This is all due to the ubiquity of search engine optimization,
这都是由于搜索引擎优化（SEO）的普遍存在
搜    索    引    擎    优    化
or SEO, the process of formatting and writing web content ways...
也就是以吸引搜索引擎爬虫和算法的方式
that appeal to search engine crawlers and algorithms.
来格式化和编写网络内容的过程
SEO however, is less straightforward than it sounds.
然而   SEO 并不像听起来那么简单
In reality, search engine optimization, as a field is constantly changing,
实际上   搜索引擎优化作为一个不断变化的门道
feeds off of infrequent and ambiguous hints that Google reveals about its algorithm,
对谷歌算法非常依赖   但它的披露既缓慢又模棱两可
requires ample trial and error.
并需要大量的试错
As you may have guessed, is fraught with ostensibly know-it-all gurus
正如你可能已经猜到的那样
and a hefty dose of snake oil.
这一领域充满了无所不知的“大师”和大量的“万金油”
I'm not alone for my contempt for how SEO practices have sterilized and homogenized the internet.
我并不是唯一一个蔑视 SEO 的应用如何冲销和同质化互联网的人
However, in many ways, it's a monster of Google own making.
然而   在许多方面   它是谷歌自己制造的怪物
As one writer puts it,
正如一位记者所说
Google has been playing an endless game of whack-a-mole...
谷歌一直在玩一场没完没了的“打鼹鼠”游戏
trying to combat SEO marketers from abusing Google's algorithm...
试图通过给他们的网站提供权威内容的所有伪装
for their own benefit by giving their sites all the trappings of authoritative content.
来打击 SEO 营销人员滥用谷歌的算法   为自己谋取利益
And naturally with more traffic, you're able to make more money by serving ads or,
自然   流量越大   你就越可以加广告来赚钱
by funneling users into using your product or service.
或吸引用户使用你的产品或服务
And even on sites with useful content,
而且即使是有有用内容的网站
you oftentimes have to scroll through a whole dissertation to find what you're looking for.
你有时也要浏览一整篇页面来寻找你要的东西
because many sites cater to the tastes of Google algorithm
因为许多网站迎合的是谷歌搜索算法
and not the end user trying to find answers on the Internet.
而非试图寻找答案的终端用户
Frequently sucks.
这往往很糟糕
Like I said before, more often than not,
正如我之前所说   更多的时候
you're more likely to find what you're looking for by a pending Reddit to the end of your query...
你更可能通过在搜索内容上加一个“reddit”
and then digging through forums.
在红迪之类的论坛中挖掘   来找到你要的东西
Alternatively, many youngsters have started using TikTok as a search engine,
作为替代   很多年轻人开始用抖音作为搜索引擎
seeking more authentic and personal sources of information that way.
那样可以寻找更真实的、更个性的信息来源
Even Google has admitted that around 40% of Gen-Zers...
连谷歌自己也承认   40% 的 Z 世代
go to TikTok or Instagram instead of Google for certain search queries.
选择抖音或者照片墙来搜寻某些东西   而非谷歌
And it's not just the results are less helpful,
这不仅仅是结果更没用的事
there are also dangerous implications for Internet history,
这对互联网的历史有着危险的影响
In the pursuit of hosting evergreen content —
为了追求托管“常青内容”
常    青    内    容
content that will reliably attract an audience long term,
也就是能够可靠地长期吸引受众的内容
articles and blog posts are constantly rewritten.
文章和博文不断被重写
New hyperlinks, better headings, better headlines, better copy.
新的超链接   更好的标题   更好的文案
This is all done to make the content more marketable and to continue to drive users to it.
这样做都是为了使内容更有市场   并推动用户继续使用它
However, there's something sad about history being rewritten with little to no disclosure.
然而   在几乎没有披露的情况下   历史被改写是一件可悲的事情
Web publishers also frequently prune content on their sites that is out of date or not in vogue.
网络出版商也经常删减他们网站上过时的或不流行的内容
内    容    删    减
As another writer puts it this all results in...
正如另一位作家所说
an Internet with no institutional memory or accountability.
这一切导致了一个没有集体记忆和问责制度的互联网
So when Google and Bing announced that...
因此当谷歌与必应宣布
generative AI responses will be taking center stage in search going forward,
生成性人工智能响应将在未来的搜索中占据中心位置时
some people hailed this as an incredible development,
一些人欢呼这是一个令人难以置信的发展
hoping that would actually give users the answers that they are looking for more quickly.
希望这将真正给用户提供他们正在寻找的答案
Others have held it as the death of SEO as these generative AI responses,
其他人则认为   生成式人工智能昭示着 SEO 的死亡
while they cite where they get their information from,
生成式人工智能会扼杀很大一部分的有机搜索流量
will kill off a good chunk of organic search traffic.
尽管它们自己也要引用这些信息
And from the looks of things, it looks like generative AI responses in search...
目前来看   搜索中的生成性人工智能响应似乎很糟糕
just flat out sucks and causes more problems than it solves.
造成的问题比它解决的要多
It flat out plagiarize some responses and the parts...
有些响应分明就是抄来的
that doesn't play to rise are often just wrong,
而那些没有发挥作用的部分也往往是错误的
because it just strings words together that it thinks are likely to appear next to each other.
因为它只是将它认为可能彼此相邻出现的单词串在一起
In order for it to deliver the quality of user experience people expect,
为了让它提供人们所期望的高质量的用户体验
it would be better sometimes just for to flat out plagiarize.
有时直接抄也不失为一种好方法
But that comes at the cost of...
但这样做的代价是
screwing over the people who made the information available in the first place.
直接侵害了那些提供信息的人
Also, since its scraping sites that are often written to be optimized for search,
另外   既然它抓取的网站都是给搜索引擎优化的
I expect that we'll see plenty of situations...
我想我们会大量遇到一种情况
where it's just gonna be garbage in, garbage out.
即   喂给它垃圾   吐出来也是垃圾
I mean there are situations where users themselves...
一定会有连用户自己
can't even find the information that they're looking for.
也无法找到他们寻找的信息的情况
And Google/Bing’s generative AI models...
而且谷歌与必应的语言模型
are gonna be looking at the exact same web pages that the users are going through.
所参考的页面   和人类用户浏览的页面是完全一样的
So I sincerely doubt that these generative responses...
所以我真的怀疑这些生成式机器人
will be able to do what users can't.
能否做人类用户也做不到的事
And to make matters worse,
更糟糕的是
Google and Bing have both announced that they'll be placing ads...
谷歌和必应都表明
into their generative search responses,
他们要在人工智能生成的结果中投放广告
meaning that even when these generative responses turn out to be useful,
意味着哪怕生成的回复有用
they'll be riddled with ads,
也会充满广告
making the user experience all the more tedious.
让用户体验变得十分乏味
Google and Bing are putting more junk in between the user and the information they're looking for...
谷歌与必应在用户与他们寻找的信息之间塞满垃圾
and essentially are punishing sites that have good information for having good information.
而且本质上在惩罚拥有优质内容的网站   理由就是优质内容本身
As far as I can tell,
在我看来
when these models have good information to work with,
当这些模型有优质的信息输入时
they can do some pretty amazing things,
它们的确能做许多令人惊叹的事
but that's just not how the Internet exists right now.
但这并非互联网现在存在的方式
Maybe it's a technical problem that can be solved over time, but,
也许这是一个随着时间推移可以解决的技术问题
nonetheless, it's still pretty shameful and condescending for companies...
但尽管如此   科技公司急不可耐地将尚待完善的东西推向大众
to push something so broken onto the masses so quickly,
并对其能力作出巨大的承诺
and to greatly over promise on its capabilities.
这仍然是相当可耻和居高临下的
Back when search engines first came out of the scene,
在搜索引擎刚出现的时候
they solved a very specific problem,
它们解决了一个非常具体的问题
and made all corners of the Internet accessible in one place.
使互联网的所有角落都能在一个地方找到
But today it feels like that most search engines have abandoned that commitment —
但今天   人们感觉大多数搜索引擎已经放弃了这个承诺
user-centricity.
以用户为中心
And while Google has been taking steps to provide search results...
尽管谷歌正在采取措施
that connect users to real world experiences,
来提供能将用户与现实世界经验连接的搜索结果
it's obvious that connecting users with this sort of content directly is not Google’s priority.
让用户能直达此类内容显然已经不是谷歌的第一考虑了
Only through a commitment to user empowerment...
只有通过对用户赋能的承诺
can we hope to restore the value and utility of online search...
我们才能希望在一个由算法和人工智能主导的时代
in an era dominated by algorithms and AI.
恢复在线搜索的价值和效用
第      四      章
互  联  网  的  守  门  人
Recently, some YouTube users have gotten notices that...
最近   一些油管用户收到通知
they'll be required to disable their AD block going forward,
要求他们停用广告屏蔽器来继续访问油管
or otherwise opt into YouTube Premium.
或者说开通油管会员
I'm a little surprised that they haven't done this a while ago but,
我有点惊讶   他们之前也没这么干
yet again, we're at a crossroad where the user experience continues to suffer.
然而   我们再一次遇到了用户体验大打折扣的十字路口
But honestly, there's a more insidious and potentially harmful set of changes happening that...
但说实话   还有一套更隐蔽、更有潜在危害的变化正在发生
I haven't really heard anyone discuss too much.
而我还没有听到太多人讨论
That's Chrome transition to its Manifest V3 extension platform.
就是 Chrome 向 Manifest V3 拓展平台迁移
A manifest file is one of the many files required in a Chrome extension...
清单文件是 Chrome 拓展中许多必需文件中的一个
and defines the level of access to browser data and system resources...
它定义了拓展能访问浏览器数据与系统资源的层级
that it requires as well as its capabilities.
拓展的清单文件和它的实际逻辑都是必需的
Back in 2018, Google announced the beginning of their transition to Manifest V3,
早在 2018 年   谷歌就宣布了他们要过渡到 Manifest V3
replacing Manifest V2.
以替代 Manifest V2
While the timeline of this transition has been delayed a handful of times,
尽管迁移时间一拖再拖
虽然 Manifest V3 因为干掉了广告类插件和油猴类插件而包受争
议（2021 年，四大浏览器开发商成立一个工作组 WECG 旨在通
过沟通与利益牵制，解决各家 API 不统一的问题），但是 V3 限制
扩展对系统资源的使用这个目标是很成功的。而且 V3 经过多年打
磨，反而还利好像 DualSub 这样的插件。应辩证看待 V3 的推广。
there are some serious consequences associated with these new specifications.
新规范将带来一些严重的后果
The big one being that it will undermine the effectiveness of AD block extensions...
第一件大事就是它会破坏去广告插件的有效性
and extensions that anonymous user information.
以及匿名化插件的能力
While Google is asserting that these changes to the manifest are for the sake of privacy —
虽然谷歌宣称对清单的这些改变是为了保护隐私
something that many developers dispute,
对这点   许多开发者表示异议
it conveniently will also have the effect of having websites show more ads,
它也容易会让网站显示更多广告
which is what Google whole business model is based around.
而这正是谷歌整个商业模式的基础
The scariest part is that these changes won't be limited to just Chrome.
最吓人的部分是   这个影响并不限于 Chrome
They'll affect all Chromium-based browsers like Edge, Brave, Opera, and more.
它影响的是所有 Chromium 内核的浏览器   如 Edge、Brave、Opera
The only web browser of note that has pushed back against these changes is Firefox,
值得注意的唯一一个反对这些更改的浏览器是火狐
saying that they'll continue to support web requests blocking features from Manifest V2,
它表示将继续支持 Manifest V2 的网络请求阻止功能
which are the foundation of anti-tracking extensions and AD blockers.
这是反跟踪扩展和广告屏蔽器的基础
But that's what we get when one company essentially becomes the gatekeeper for...
但当一家公司基本上成为访问互联网的守门人时
access to the Internet.
我们就会得到这种结果
Once they have that power,
一旦他们拥有这种权力
it's only a matter of time before they use it for their own benefit.
他们将其用于自己的利益只是时间问题
So like I said at the beginning of the video,
正如我在视频开头所说
a lot of futurists did become fascists later in life.
很多未来主义者在后来变成了法西斯
However, that was not a universal rule.
然而   这并非一个逃不开的普遍规则
Futurism actually found a home on all sides of the political spectrum.
未来主义在各个政治派别都找到了归宿
That's because while some tenets of Marinetti’s Futurist Manifesto were reactionary,
因为   尽管《未来主义宣言》的一些条款是反动的
the core of the futurism project was not.
未来主义的内核却不是
The one thing that I think the futurist movement deserves a lot of praise for...
我认为未来主义运动值得高度赞扬的一件事是
is that it brought into the mainstream, a new found optimism for the future.
它将一种新发现的对未来的乐观情绪带入了主流
They glorified technological advancement because they saw good in it.
他们赞美技术进步   因为他们看到了其中的好处
They celebrated human ingenuity as a freeing force.
他们赞美人类的创造力是一股解放的力量
Over 100 years later, though,
然而   100 多年后的今天
I struggle to find that sense of optimism, at least regards the modern Internet.
我很难找到那种乐观的感觉   至少在现代互联网方面是这样
It seems like there's a roadblock on every road to progress.
似乎每一条前进的道路上都有路障
Or any progress that's been made on the Internet is being ratcheted backwards.
或者   互联网上取得的任何进展都在倒退
When corporations put the onus of their growth onto the shoulders of its users,
当企业将增长的责任放在用户的肩上时
nothing good can come of it.
不会有任何好处
And unfortunately, that's what we're seeing more and more of lately.
不幸的是   最近这种情况愈见愈多
While doing research for this video,
在为这个视频做研究时
I came across one article that I think perfectly encapsulates where we're headed.
我看到了一篇文章   我认为它完美地概括了我们的方向
"We are living through the end of the useful Internet.
我们正在经历有用的互联网的终结
The future is informed discussion behind locked doors in discord and private fora.
在未来   网络讨论将在各个圈子内闭门进行   变得嘈杂而封闭
With the public facing web increasingly filled with detritus...
由大型语言模型产生的   仅在风格上与有用信息相似的垃圾
generated by LLMs bearing only a stylistic resemblance to useful information,
逐渐在面向公众的网络上横行
finding unbiased and independent product reviews,
寻找客观的独立产品评论
expert tech support and all manner of helpful advice...
专家技术支持和各种有用的建议
will now resemble the process by which one now searches for illegal sports streams
现在将类似于人们搜索非法体育节目
or pirated journal articles.
或盗版期刊文章的过程
The decades of real human conversation posted at places like Reddit...
在红迪等地方发布的数十年的真实人类对话
will prove useful training material for the mindless bots and deceptive marketers that replace it.”
将沦为无意识机器人和欺骗性营销者的有用的培训材料   而后者最终会取代前者
While the recent blackouts by several subreddits are certainly admirable,
尽管最近红迪版主的下线抗议固然值得敬佩
it doesn't change the fact that Reddit and all of the other companies I've talked about...
这也改变不了一个事实
have ownership of these platforms.
真正捏着网络平台的   不是网民   是红迪这些公司
They are businesses who have a legal obligation to maximize their profit for their investors,
他们是有法律义务为投资者实现利润最大化的企业
and can make whatever changes they like, regardless of our own feelings.
可以做出任何他们喜欢的改变   而不管我们自己的感受如何
But nonetheless, this would be the end of the Internet as we know it.
但尽管如此   正如我们所知   这将是互联网的终结
Entire networks of people, incredibly passionate people across all sorts of sites...
整个网络的人   各种网站上充满激情的人
are at risk of breaking down or eroding away,
都有崩溃或被侵蚀的风险
or hiding in some shadowy corner,
或者被雪藏在某个阴暗的角落里
and that's just such a sad and unthinkable prospect.
这是一个如此可悲和不可想象的前景
It's crucial to address these trends to ensure that the Internet...
应对这些趋势至关重要
remains a vibrant and inclusive space for innovation and collaboration.
以确保互联网仍然是一个充满活力和包容性的创新和协作空间
By advocating for this openness,
通过倡导开放
supporting developers and independent creators,
支持开发者和独立创作者
and demanding transparency,
并要求企业更加透明
we can hopefully work towards a more interconnected...
我们有望努力实现一个更加互联和用户友好的互联网
and user-friendly Internet actually enriches our lives.
这实际上丰富了我们的生活
I've been 1C2.
我是 1C2
Thanks for watching.
感谢收看